我也为你生气  戴安
I'm mad for you, Diane.
罗杰这么快就重返情场了吗
Roger's dating already?
天啊  我好好奇她是不是比他年轻
OMG, I wonder if she's younger than him.
请稍等
You hold on a second.
罗琳  我最爱的客户过得如何呀
Lorraine, how's my favorite client?
我最近的事业红得发紫
I've been on something of a hot streak at work.
我接了一大堆新客户
I've tapped into a rich vein of new clients --
都是刚离婚的妈妈们
recently divorced moms.
你可以说我挖到了"单亲妈妈矿"
You might say I hit the single-mother lode.
主卧室合你心意吗
How about that master suite, huh?
要是有人共享就好了
Maybe if I had someone to share it with.
罗琳  你风韵犹存  是抢手的高价货
Lorraine, you are a beautiful woman with a lot to offer.
要给这房子也出个价吗
Should we make an offer?
房子是很棒  可惜我单身一人
It's a great house, but I'm just gonna be alone.
戴安  你怎么会单身一人
Diane, you're not gonna be alone.
你只需要贷一个款
You're gonna get a loan.
拿着苏打  零食  我们去地下室玩牌
Sodas, snacks -- poker game's in the basement.
我比你更需要睡眠
Look, I need more sleep than you,
但自从他们把那颗梅树砍了
and ever since they cut down that stupid prune tree,
每天早晨阳光就会照得我睡不着
the sun has been right in my eyes every morning.
不是梅树  是他们在修枝剪叶
It's not a prune tree. They pruned the tree.
[Prune:梅子/修剪]
我是不会和你换床的
And I'm not switching places with you,
你下次掉个头睡就行了
so you should just put your head at the other end of the bed.
什么啊  要我的脚枕着枕头睡吗
Uh, why? So my feet get the pillow?
竟然还说我傻
And I'm the dumb one.
戴安  你不能老想着他
Diane, you have got to forget about him.
罗杰现在是夏安的问题了
Roger's Cheyenne's problem now.
-亲爱的  -知道吗
- Honey... - You know what?
你需要找人倾诉
You need to talk.
一起去星巴克喝杯饮料吧
Starbucks for a little go juice?
怎么啦
What is up?
我得去一趟办公室
I need to go into the office.
我爸叫我把月记录总结好[月事]
My dad wants me to close out the monthly.
怎么了
What?
月事  没事  你继续
Monthly. Never mind. Go on.
我今天会很累  所以需要你
I'm stretched a little thin today, so I need you
去买点杂货  照顾一下孩子
to do the grocery shopping, check in on the kids,
或许再顺便把前院的树枝清理了
and maybe clean up those branches in the front yard.
放心加放心
Done and done.
这是个词组
Is that an expression,
还是你真的只记住了我刚才说过的两件事
or did you really only remember two of the things I said?
-后者  -我会给你语音留言备忘的
- The second. - I'll leave you a message.
你好啊
Hello?
菲尔
Phil.
不好意思  再打一次
Sorry. Call back.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：坏D小泡  Olivia_xuxu  二千  小蛮腰  3CC醉芝士
时间轴：加森    校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第三集
我有坏消息  杰
I have bad news, Jay.
乔被赶出金宝贝乐园了
Joe was thrown out of the gymboree.
又被赶出来了  出什么事了
Again? What happened?
他推倒了梅森  把他弄哭了
He pushed Mason. He made him cry.
老师说不准我们再去
The teacher said that we cannot go back.
太荒谬了  梅森是大孩子了
That's ridiculous. Mason's a big baby.
去那里玩的都是大孩子
Everybody there is a big baby.
但乔玩的时候很凶
But Joe plays very rough.
原因我们都知道  是诅咒
And we know why. It's the curse.
虽然我从来不反对你小点声说话
Not that I'd ever want to discourage you from whispering,
但根本没有诅咒这回事
but that's not a thing.
我的家族有恶魔诅咒
There is a mark of the devil in my family.
我的曾曾祖父
My great-great grandfather
得到了翡翠矿址
was given the location of an emerald mine
却换走了他的灵魂
in exchange for his soul.
有文件之类的记录此事吗
There's, like, paperwork or something that proves this?
他们说在他女儿的婚礼上
And they say that the day of his daughter's wedding,
一只大鸟从天而降
a great bird came from the sky
用爪子一把抓住他
and snatched him with his claws
把他带到遥远的地方去了
and took him far, far away.
你知道你讲过的许多故事的结局
You're aware that a remarkable number of your stories end
都是某个家庭成员被大鸟抓走吧
with a family member being carried off by a giant bird.
他们确实是这样告诉我的  杰
I only know what I was told, Jay.
我只是说如果那种事发生超过三次
I'm just saying after the third time,
我们应该以后举办室内聚会
we might think about moving the party inside.
好吧  也许不是诅咒
Okay, maybe it's not the curse,
但你知道我的家族是有黑暗面的
but you know that my family has a very dark side.
我的表亲奥雷利奥是个偷马贼
My cousin Aurelio is a horse thief.
我叔叔卡洛斯幕后操控足球赛  我阿姨
My uncle Carlos fixed soccer games. My aunt --
他是教他们把球捡起来
Did he teach them to pick the ball up
用手扔到场地里吗
and throw it down the field?
因为只有那样才能操控足球
'Cause that's the only way you fix soccer.
曼尼逃脱了诅咒  但乔我就不知道了
Manny escaped it, but I am not sure about Joe.
歌洛莉亚  是老师太紧张了
Gloria, this is about an uptight teacher.
就算乔有点调皮又怎样
And so what if Joe's a little boisterous?
不是一直都说要让孩子保留真实的风格吗
Whatever happened to letting kids be themselves?
-我准备好了  -把帽子摘了
- Ready. - Lose the hat.
看来我看《音乐之声》都要戴普通帽子了
I guess I'm supposed to see "Sound of Music" in a regular hat.
我不反对《音乐之声》
Nothing against "Sound of Music,"
但今天下午
but there's a lot of other things
我们可以做很多其他事
we could do this afternoon.
你听说过《猛龙怪客》吗[1974年电影]
You ever hear of "Death Wish"?
我喜欢"死亡之愿"
Oh, I love "Death Wish."
曼尼  那是有病的孩子参加的慈善活动
Manny, that's the charity where the sick kids go to,
比如去麦当娜的音乐会
like, a concert with Madonna
或者和贾斯丁・比伯看超级杯  或者
or to the super bowl with Justin Bieber, or they --
不不不
No, no, no, no, no.
我说的是电影  70年代的
It's a movie -- New York, '70s,
查尔斯・布朗森扮演一个顾家的好男人
Charles Bronson's a firm family man, and he...
但被逼到绝境
Who's pushed to the limit
于是他决定作出反击
until one day he decides to fight back.
-你看过  -片名是《猛龙怪客》这么明显
- You've seen it? - It's called "Death Wish."
我猜结局就是他在公寓里
I doubt it ends with him trading banter
和玛莎・梅森互相调侃
in an apartment with Marsha Mason.
你好啊  未婚夫
Hey, fiance?
你好  我的亲夫
Hello, my intended.
那听起来像是在说"谋杀亲夫"
That one sounds a little murdery.
你就是我的亲夫啊
You are my intended.
别说了  别这样
Stop it. Stop it!
你出去的时候
So, while you're out,
我会重新看一下选什么花
I'm gonna review our flower options,
目前为止我很中意"福劳莱与哈代"花店
and I have to say, so far, i'm partial to Floral and Hardy,
[与著名喜剧《劳莱与哈代》谐音]
但我还要最后看一眼"阿甘花店"的花
but I'm gonna give one last look at Florist Gump.
[与名电影《阿甘正传》谐音]
你就喜欢选名字起得好的
You love a business with a clever name.
确实  被你发现了
I do. Guilty.
我真是太喜欢现在的状态了
Can I just say I love how this is going?
米奇尔和我一致同意
Mitchell and I agreed
由我来操办婚礼事宜
that I would be in charge of the wedding
上周我们才听说安迪家的悲剧
after the tragic news last week from the Andys.
不是指那条山脉[安第斯山]
Uh, not the mountain range. No.
我们的朋友安德鲁和安德鲁
Our friends Andrew and Andrew --
他们分手了
they broke up.
筹划婚礼的压力太大
The stress of planning a wedding was too much.
他们互相吹毛求疵  争论
They were quibbling about...
每一件事
Everything.
所以我很乐意
I mean, uh, which is why I'm just happy
放任他去发挥
to stay out of his way.
对  我构思远大  然后再精简
Yeah, I dream big. Then I winnow down.
构思远大  再精简
Dream big. Winnow down.
-构思远大  -好了  放下来
- Dream big. - Okay, winnow down.
没错  别挡着我  抱歉
Yep. Stay out of my way. Sorry.
二爸  拉里哪去了
Daddy, where's Larry?
亲爱的  你知道猫总爱瞎跑的
Oh, well, you know how cats are, sweetie.
他们是  流浪之神
They're -- they're wanderers.
但我都好几天没见着他了
But I haven't seen him in days.
没事  他会回家的  好吗
Well, he'll be back, okay?
这事你得信我
Trust daddy on this.
好吧
Okay.
我有点担心
You know, I'm starting to get worried
拉里可能不会回来了
that Larry might not come back.
-一定已经死了  -什么
- Oh, he's definitely dead. - What?!
不是横尸街头就是已入狼口了
Yeah, street meat or coyote chow.
我们再等几周  再弄只新的
We'll wait a couple weeks, and then we'll get a new Larry.
你对我们宠物的生死有点冷漠啊
Uh, you're pretty nonchalant about our family pet dying.
我们难道不应该帮助闺女度过这一关吗
And shouldn't we help our daughter process this loss?
应该  应该  她会没事的
Yes, we will, and she'll be fine.
我也不是冷漠
And it's not nonchalant.
农场生活就这样  动物死亡很正常
It's farm life. Death is everywhere.
别对他们投入太多情感就行了
You just learn to not get too attached to anything.
这么说  要是我死了
Oh, so, what, if I were to die,
你就等几周然后找个人取代我吗
you would just wait a few weeks and then replace me?
别说傻话
Of course not.
我上哪儿去找一个跟你
Where would I find another gay Mitchell
一模一样的同性恋米奇尔呢
with your exact markings?
大艾艾  干嘛呢
What's happening, big Al?
再管我叫那名字试试看
Yeah, let's go ahead and veto that nickname.
罗本教会我一个特棒的把戏
Hey, Reuben taught me this cool trick.
眼睛闭上
Close your eyes.
我的天  你们什么毛病啊
Oh, my god! What is wrong with you?
妹子让你亲了  现在谁也不欠谁
You kissed a girl. Now we're even.
我打扑克牌输给他了
Just paying off a poker debt.
卢克的变态朋友刚刚强吻了我
Luke's creepy friend just kissed me.
好恶  罗本吗  那个小怪胎吗
Ew. Reuben? That little weirdo?
我还在这呢
I'm still here.
我得把嘴放开水里消消毒
I'm gonna go boil my mouth.
兄弟们  去楼下玩游戏
Oh, hey, guys. Game's downstairs.
你们这些笨蛋玩的游戏
This little game you dorks play,
赌注到底大不大
we talking milk money or heavy cream?
好些刚收的成人礼礼金呢
A lot of fresh bar mitzvah money down there.
我能参加吗
Mind if I sit in?
我们有规定不能带女的
We kind of got a no-girls policy.
是规定还是根本没姑娘要跟你们玩
Is it a policy or just something that keeps happening?
后者啦
The second.
亲爱的  怎么了
Hey, honey.
我激动得都不能自已了
I am so excited I can't stand it!
你那手要是再那么扑腾
If you're gonna move your hands around like that,
还是先把电话放下  别摔了
you need to put the phone down.
好的  好的  好的
Okay, okay, okay.
餐前鸡尾酒会的部分
For cocktail hour,
他们在为我们设计一座人造瀑布
they're creating a running waterfall
我们两个拥抱的全息影像
onto which they're going to project
会被投影到瀑布上面
a hologram of us embracing.
但我们还是要注重简化  对吧
But we're still winnowing, right?
那已经很精简了
Already winnowed.
我舍弃了天使装呢
I cut the angel costumes.
好难抉择的  米奇尔
Hard choices, Mitchell.
好的  我得挂了  太激动啦
Okay, I got to go. I'm so excited!
好吧  我也是
Yeah, me too.
我和小卡恋爱最棒的地方在于什么
Best thing about my relationship with Cam?
在于信任
Trust.
快讯一则  我强迫症犯起来也不是人
Newsflash -- I can be an obsessive person.
在以前  我根本没法放手让别人
In the past, I've had trouble letting someone else
做决定
call the shots.
把大权拱手让人实在令我抓狂
Giving up control made me crazy.
那也是我跟小卡相处得如此轻松的原因
That's what makes my life with Cam so freeing.
我能把大事交由他处理
I can turn over big things to him
然后自己不再去担心
and never give them a second thought.
眼不见  心不烦  拜拜了您
Out of sight, out of mind. Bye-bye.
菲尔
Phil.
这也
This is --
我的天啊
Oh! Oh, my god!
菲尔
Phil?
-菲尔你在吗  -我就坐那儿
- Phil?! - Yeah, I was just sitting there,
他就猥亵我了
and he basically molested me.
你说什么
Excuse me?
她说的是罗本
She's talking about Reuben.
你又是谁
Who are you?!
你们男的最好把钱带够了
You boys better have money.
不给钱姐可不干
I am not doing this for free.
你们  你们要干嘛
W-w-what's -- what's happening?
我听明白了  乔伊斯
Oh, I hear you, Joyce.
他的时间宝贵  你的就不宝贵  是吧
His time's important. Your time isn't, right?
一会打给你  超级巨星
Let me buzz you back, superstar.
好嘞
Okay.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
前院的树枝还在那
Branches are still in the front yard,
我脸都被弹肿了
I just took a rake to the face,
罗本对艾丽克斯有奇怪的企图
Reuben is getting really weird on Alex,
海莉为了钱在地下室不知做什么呢
And Haley's doing something for money in the basement.
没什么大不了啦
It's all gonna be fine.
老爸回来了  超级巨星
Daddy's home, superstar.
别  别那么叫我
No. Don't call me that.
我跟那些粘人的离婚妇女不一样
I'm not one of your needy little divorces.
那是我的工作而已
Um, that is work.
是吗
Is it?
因为我觉得你都爱上
'Cause I kind of feel like part of you loves
充当这些女人的英雄了
being a hero to those women.
我是在帮助她们
I'm a helper of people.
你当初追我这个房产中介的时候
Hey, you knew what you signed up for
就应当料到会有这些后果了
when you hitched your wagon to a realtor man.
亲爱的  我们认识时
Honey, when I met you,
你还是个婚礼DJ
you were a wedding deejay.
顺便说一句  DJ先生
By the way, Spinderfella,
看样子你还得去趟杂货店
looks like you still need to hit the grocery store.
我觉得某人感到被冷落了
I think someone's feeling neglected.
没错  我跟很多寂寞妇女打交道
Yes, I deal with a lot of lonely women,
但我娶了的寂寞妇女只有你一个
but there's only one I'm married to.
你有点忘乎所以了  菲尔
You're getting too involved, Phil.
你在哄骗这些女人
You are juggling these women,
而你水平其实很有限
and you're not that good a juggler.
你是在说气话
Now you're just lashing out!
来这边
Hey, come here.
我没告诉杰
I didn't tell Jay,
但有时候连我自己都害怕乔
but sometimes Joe even scares me.
万幸的是  有专业人士
Lucky for me, there are professionals
来帮我解决这些问题
that are trained to deal with such problems.
您好  谢谢您过来  神父
Ay, thank you for coming, padre.
小事一桩  歌洛莉亚
Oh, of course, Gloria.
这肯定是弗汉希欧啦
And this must be Fulgencio.
小伙子真帅呀
What a beautiful little boy.
他天性纯良
He's such a sweet nature.
我能看得出他本性善良
I can tell he's a gentle soul.
弗汉希欧  松手  松手
Ah! Hey, Fulgencio, no, no.
抱歉  神父
Sorry, padre.
这也正是我找您来的原因
Ay, that's why I called you, Father.
我觉得这个孩子很坏
I think he's bad.
我的家族有恶魔诅咒
There is evil in my family.
歌洛莉亚  他还只是个婴儿呢
Ah, Gloria, he's just a little baby.
上礼拜  他眼睛变红了
Last week, his eyes got red,
连狗都被他吓跑了
and the dog backed away.
他可能只是感冒了而已
He probably just had a cold.
每个妈妈都喜欢担心
All mothers worry.
你看他  气色红润  乖乖地玩积木呢
Look at him -- rosy cheeks, he's playing with his blocks.
又是六
The six again.
因为乔推到了一个小孩  就把他开除
So, Joe knocks one kid down, he's out.
小孩子都这样
All kids do that.
不然你那整栋楼怎么都是防撞材料造的
Why do you think your whole building is made out of nerf?
是啊  你现在知道我小孩的脾气随谁了
Yeah, you see where he gets it from.
听着  我可不怕你  黛比老师
Hey, listen, I'm not afraid of you, Miss Debbie.
你不是...该死
You're not the -- damn it.
看来某人该去纳粹占领的奥地利
Sounds like someone needs a relaxing trip
来个放松之旅了
to nazi-occupied Austria.
她居然挂我电话
Can't believe she hung up on me.
谁让你冲着人家吼来着
Well, you were yelling at her.
我这是坚持原则  是不同的
Standing up for yourself is not the same thing as, uh --
你等会
Excuse me.
算了吧  杰
Uh, come on, Jay.
你家没家教的
So no one ever taught you manners, huh?
你想怎样
Whatever, dude.
你撞了人就应该道歉
No, you bump into somebody, you apologize.
既然我都要给你上一课了
And since I'm teaching you something here,
就先从"好好穿裤子"开始吧
here's a little class called "Intro to pants."
杰  住手
Jay, stop!
放开我
Get off me!
我和那些孩子是同校生
I go to school with those kids.
你知不知道你这样多丢人
You know how embarrassing that was?
-曼尼  -别说了
- Manny. - No.
你为什么老是这样
Why do you always got to be like this --
爱评判别人  脾气爆  还大嗓门
judgmental, hot-tempered, loud?
这些都是我最讨厌的事
These are a few of my least-favorite things.
菲尔・邓菲  房源出售
我看得出你跟这房子有缘  戴安
Well, I can see that the house speaks to you, Diane.
"买下我吧"
"Buy me."
现在还不行
Not now, house.
开放式的布局  宽敞的厨房  多好
Ah, the open floor plan, the spacious kitchen.
我确实很喜欢
I do love it.
是我办公室打来的
That's -- that's the office.
我何不再去后院最后看上一眼呢
Why don't you take one last look at the backyard?
有没有想到"露天烧烤"
Did someone say barbecue?
我有哦
"I did."
罗琳  怎么了
Lorraine, what is up?
没忙什么呀  就在办公室呗
Nothing. Just kicking it at the office.
慢点慢点
Slow down, now.
有什么事跟菲尔说
Tell Phil what happened.
菲尔  我能不能去车库看看
Phil, can I go in the garage?
你就把这当自己家  随意  妹妹
Make yourself at home, sister.
刚才是我妹妹  她来看我
That was my sister who is visiting town
顺便看看我办公室
-- and my office,
我就是从办公室打给你的
which is where I am calling you from.
是你打给我的
You called me.
我很担心拉里
I'm worried about Larry.
宝贝儿  我知道
Oh, honey, I know.
他去哪了
Where is he?
莉莉  有件事也许我该告诉你
Um, Lily, there's probably something I should tell you.
拉里不会回来了
Larry's not coming back home.
为什么  他死了吗
Why? Is he dead?
不  他没死
Nope. Um, not dead.
拉里遇到了意中人
Larry, uh, met someone, fell in love,
结婚了
and he got married.
他们会来探望我们吗
Are they ever going to visit?
恐怕不会  因为当猫结婚以后
I'm afraid not because when cats get married,
他们就必须搬去树林里
they have to move to, um, the forest,
这样就不会受到城市里其它猫的诱惑
and so then they're not tempted by other cats in the city.
-那是拉里呀  -我知道
- It's Larry. - I know.
就算是你平时认为坚强的人
Even people that you would never expect
-也会有软弱的时候  -不  在那
- have moments of weakness. - No, over there.
可是他妻子呢
But where's his wife?
你好  拉里
Hello, Larry.
拉里回来了
Larry's back.
你知道吗
Yeah, uh, well, you know what?
我猜他俩可能不合适
I think they probably, uh, didn't work out,
于是就分手了
and they broke up.
结婚了以后还能分手吗
People get married and then break up?
要是你和爸爸也分手呢
What if that happens to you and daddy?
你知道吗  是爸爸搞错了
Oh, y-you know what? Daddy made a mistake.
拉里和他的妻子没有分手
Uh, Larry and his wife didn't break up.
拉里的妻子  去世了
Larry's wife...died.
不是吧
Oh, no.
是啊
Yeah.
所以我们要给拉里一个了结
That's why we're gonna give him the closure he needs
我们要给他的妻子
by throwing, um, a funeral
举行一场葬礼来纪念她精彩的一生
to celebrate the remarkable life of Larry's wife.
葬礼会很棒的  你知道吗
It's gonna be great. You know what?
我们会准备现场音乐  还有鞋盒
We're gonna have music, we're gonna get a shoe box...
还有蜡烛
...we're gonna have candles.
喂  阿甘花店  又是我
Yes. Hi, Florist Gump. It's me again.
独自解决这个危机的感觉真好
It felt good to handle that crisis on my own.
在过去  我肯定第一时间找米奇尔求助
In the past, I would have had to run to Mitchell,
但是他现在越来越信任我了
but he's been trusting me more and more.
我真为他骄傲
I'm so proud of him.
他真的学会了放手
He's really learned to let things go.
不  天啊  不  不  不
Oh, no! God, no, no, no!
干吗
What?
我们在楼下被血洗了
It's a bloodbath down there.
输得分文不剩
We lost everything.
你不是很厉害吗
I thought you were good.
我总是能赢迪兰呀
I always beat Dylan.
求你了  我们需要你
Come on. We need your help.
你是家里扑克打得最好的人了
You're the best card player in this family.
我有什么好处
What's in it for me?
-一个做好姐姐的机会  -免了
- A chance to be a good sister. - Pass.
罗本到处跟别人说
Reuben's been telling everyone
你主动跟他舌吻
you slipped him the tongue.
让开
Move.
猫不是有九条命吗
I thought cats had nine lives.
是啊  的确如此
Yeah, and they do,
但拉里的妻子比他年长
but Larry's wife was older than he was,
而且她已经结过八次婚了
and she'd been married eight times before.
就像伊丽莎白・泰勒那样吗
Like Elizabeth Taylor?
你记得我给你讲的睡前故事
Oh, you remember our bedtime stories.
迪兰  谢谢你这么快赶来
Oh, Dylan, thank you for coming on such short notice.
我需要你在这边挖个洞
I just need you to dig a hole right over here.
-谢谢  -没问题
- Thank you. - Oh, no problem.
莉莉  请节哀顺变
So, Lily, I'm really sorry.
拉里还好吗
How's Larry doing?
很好  他是只快乐的小猫
Fine. He's a happy cat.
原来是猫啊
Oh, they're cats.
这下我的工作就轻松多了
That's gonna make my job a lot easier.
好了  各位  感谢你们前来
Okay, everyone, thank you for coming.
这对莉莉很重要  对我也很重要
It means a lot to Lily, and it means a lot to me.
安格斯
Angus?
关于拉里的爱妻  我该说些什么呢
So, Larry's wife -- what can I say?
她很爱拉里
She loved Larry.
和天下所有猫夫妻一样
And, um, you know, like all cat marriages,
他们经历了起起落落
they had their ups and their downs,
但他们都一同挺了过来
but they always landed on their feet.
凿到石头了
Oh, hit a rock.
不是石头
Oh! Not a rock!
各位
Okay, everybody!
请保持冷静  保持冷静
Please stay calm! Please stay calm!
别乱跑  地很滑
No running! It's slippery!
安格斯  继续演奏
Angus, keep playing!
好
Okay.
-兰德尔  -怎么了
- Randall! - Yeah?
我在上面
I'm up here.
普里契特先生吗
Mr. Pritchett?
这都是实习工作的相关文件
This is all intern work.
不是为我的乐队打印的
It isn't for my band.
需要我去帮忙买咖啡吗
Need me to do a coffee run?
不
No.
不是  听我说  我刚刚在打扫
No, uh, listen, I was -- I was cleaning,
然后被卡在这上面了
and I got stuck up here,
我需要你去我的办公室
and I need you to go into my office
把倒下的梯子扶起来
and stand up the ladder that fell.
好的
Got it.
抱歉我刚刚撒了谎
And I'm sorry about lying before.
这是我们乐队的宣传单
Those are flyers for my band,
叫"实习生乐队"
the Interns.
你的门是锁着的
Uh-oh. Your door's locked.
糟糕
Oh, no.
但如果你可以向前挪一点
But, hey, I-I think, if you keep going forward,
然后转身把腿从通风口伸下来
then back your legs out through the vent,
我想我可以抓住你的腿把你扶下来
I can grab them to help you down.
我不确定
Oh, I don't know.
这让我有点紧张
That makes me a little nervous.
想想别的事情
Just think about something else.
我听说你要结婚了  进行得怎么样了
I heard you're getting married. How's that going?
是啊是啊
Oh, yeah, yeah.
还不错  不错
It's -- it's good. It's good.
我们正在策划婚礼
You know, we're planning it right now.
实际上  是有人在为我策划
Actually, it's being planned for me.
不错啊  毫无压力
That's nice. No stress.
本该是这样  对吧
Oh, you'd think, huh?
但事情有些失控了
But it's getting a little bit out of hand.
策划婚礼总是这样的
Oh, that happens with weddings.
是吗
Does it?
你去过几个婚礼上是有
I mean, how many weddings have you been to
"鸽子发射器"这种东西的
that have something called a dove cannon?
我觉得在这种事情上
You know, I think I should have a say
我应该也有话语权的
in something like that.
你得放手了  普里契特先生
You need to let go, Mr. Pritchett.
我做不到
I-I can't.
我希望我能做到  不我不能
I-I wish I could, but I can't.
我...这太让我抓狂了
I just -- it's freaking me out.
不  我是说我扶住你了
No, I've got you already.
好吧
Okay.
好
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很善于理解别人的想法
You know, I'm pretty good at reading people,
听起来您和您太太真的需要
and it sounds like you and your lady
通过沟通来解决问题
really need to talk this out.
是啊  也许你说得对
Yeah, maybe you're right.
我告诉你一个小秘密吧
So I'm gonna let you in on a little secret.
-我是同性恋  -天哪
- I'm gay. - Oh, my god.
她知道吗
Does she know?
得给新婚之夜留点惊喜不是吗
Got to save something for the wedding night, huh?
好了
Okay.
莱利  别这样  巴斯特  快坐下
Riley, no! Buster, please sit!
迪兰  来帮忙
Dylan, help!
我帮不了
I can't!
这些猫猫狗狗打得不可开交
These cats and dogs are fighting like -- oh!
好了  各位  很抱歉
Okay, everybody, I'm sorry.
这本该是一场小型仪式
This was supposed to be a small service,
但我没有控制好自己
but I don't winnow down.
我做得过火了
I overdo.
要是我连给猫办场假葬礼都做不好
And if I let a simple fake cat funeral get out of hand,
我要怎么才能办好整场婚礼呢
how am I supposed to plan an entire wedding?
你们迟到了
You're late.
我需要我家米奇尔
Okay, I need Mitchell.
好消息
Good news.
他刚停下车
He just pulled up.
该死
Damn it.
好  进来  快进来
Okay, in. In, in.
好  好
Yes. Okay.
能来个人把那东西抓住吗  拜托了
And, please, can somebody catch that thing?
好  好的  都留下
Okay, all right, stay.
各位...
Everyone just...
去健身感觉怎么样
Hey! How was the gym?
我没去成
I never made it.
小卡  有些事我得跟你谈谈
Listen, Cam, I got to talk about something.
我也是
I do, too.
你想不想参与到婚礼的策划中来
What would you think about being more involved with the wedding?
这正是我要谈的事
That's what I wanted to talk about.
我很乐意
I would love to.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
我就是觉得我们...我们一起会更好
You know, I just think we're -- we're better together.
"一起会更好"  我喜欢这说法
"Better together." Mm, I like that.
我无法和蛇同处一室
I cannot be in a house with snakes.
有多糟
How bad is it?
大概需要一个小时清理现场
Gonna need about an hour.
给你
Here you go.
我给你买了"雪顶"巧克力
I got you Sno-caps,
因为最后他们成功穿越阿尔卑斯雪山逃跑了
'cause, you know, at the end, they escape across the alps.
感谢剧透
Thanks for ruining it.
淡定点  这电影都出了五十年了
Calm down. The movie's 50 years old.
你真是处处"交友"啊
Making friends everywhere, aren't you?
你总是说  "要表达出你的感情"
Listen, you always say, "Express your feelings."
我生气时就是这样
When I get mad, that's what I do.
喂  我讲话方便
Hello? Yeah, I can talk.
我爸妈拉我来看一部烂片
My parents dragged me into this stupid movie.
上吧  杰  把他的手机塞他嘴里
Go ahead, Jay. Feed him his phone.
你是在说你不介意我那么做吗
You're telling me that doesn't bother you?
我听不清楚  大声点
I can't hear you. Talk louder.
我只是说
I'm just saying...
如果一有脾气就发作
...if we give in to every impulse,
那我们和禽兽就没有区别了
we're no better than wild animals.
但如果把怒气忍回去  会被活活气死的
But if we push it down, it eats you alive.
不介意不就行了吗
Not if you just let it go.
那部烂片《欢乐满人间》的女主角演的
The chick from that crapfest "Mary Poppins."
我受够了
That's it.
我妈开计程车时  我一个人在家里
A lot of cold, lonely nights in that apartment by myself
度过了很多寒冷孤独的夜
while my mom was driving a taxi,
只有一样东西陪伴我
and only one thing kept me company.
如果你对《欢乐满人间》有意见
So, you got a problem with poppins,
那就是对我有意见
you got a problem with me.
神父  真是对不起
Ay, Father, I am so sorry.
我根本不知道他可以拿起叉子
I didn't even know that he could hold a fork.
不  是我自己不好
No, no, no, I blame myself.
我不应该跟他玩"摘鼻子"游戏
I probably shouldn't have taken his nose.
不  是我家里的遗传问题
No, it's my family.
我家女孩都胸部丰满
The girls are very chesty,
但是男孩都有魔性
but the men, they're kissed by the devil.
歌洛莉亚  你这么担心
Gloria, the fact that you are so concerned
只是证明了你是一个有爱心的好妈妈
is only proof that you are a loving and caring mother.
对孩子们影响最大的是父母
It's the parents who shape the child.
你儿子的成长环境非常棒
And your son is growing up in a wonderful home.
去死吧  人渣
Die, scum!
不行不行
No, no, no!
大声点  像你刚才
Louder, like you did
在得来速快餐店那样
at the drive-through.
妈  杰和我看了《猛龙怪客》
Mom, Jay and I saw "Death Wish."
太好看了
Amazing.
曼尼在看《音乐之声》时和人打架
Manny got in a fight at "The Sound of Music,"
被赶出来了
got kicked out.
我从来没有这样骄傲过
I've never been so proud.
我想所有家庭
Well, I guess every household
都用得上一些指导和调整
could use a little fine-tuning, huh?
我给你我的名片
Let me give you my card
-上面有我手机号  -太好了
- with my cell number on it. - Please.
我的钱包去哪里了
And what did I do with my wallet? I...
我指责菲尔不帮忙
I had yelled at Phil for not helping out,
他却在那里  做我让他做的事情
and there he was, doing exactly what I had asked him to do...
西葫芦来啦
Here's our zucchini.
上来吧  小家伙
Up top, buddy.
却是在给别的家庭做
...for some other family.
你这样帮我们  你真是太好了
You are so sweet for helping me with this.
你受到了那么大的伤害  罗琳
How hurt you've been, Lorraine --
这个很好  这不算什么
This is sweet. This is...normal.
菲尔
Phil?
戴安
Diane?
你好  超级巨星
Hey, superstar.
你不是叫我超级巨星吗
I thought I was superstar.
你的丈夫对我真是太好了
Oh, your husband has been so wonderful to me.
他不是我的丈夫  他是我的房产中介
He's not my husband. He's my realtor.
他是我的房产中介
Oh, he's my realtor.
我是你们的房产中介
I'm both your realtors.
我真幸运能拥有如此...
I-I'm just lucky to have such a --
我们正准备去看房子
We're on our way to an open house.
所以你才不能带我去看
Oh, is that why you couldn't
那栋殖民风格的房子吗
show me the colonial later?
我做了你喜欢的玉米面包
I made that corn bread that you like.
我们会去看的
W-we're gonna make it to that.
我只需要结束和罗琳的事
I just have to finish up with Lorraine.
你是说  快点了结吗
Oh, you mean, like, "Get it over with"?
不  我不是那个意思
No, I-I don't mean that.
我以为你最爱吃西葫芦面包
And I thought zucchini bread was your favorite.
否则我为什么要买西葫芦
Why -- why am I buying zucchini?
一个人就不能既喜欢西葫芦面包
Hey, can't a guy like zucchini bread
又喜欢玉米面包吗
and corn bread?
-菲尔  -见鬼
- Phil? - Damn it.
罗妮
Ronnie!
你不是说去看医生吗
I thought you had a doctor's appointment.
所以你才没能去看达雷尔的游泳比赛
That's why you had to miss Darrell's swim meet.
她是谁
Who's she?
只是另一位客户
Just another client.
"Just another client"?
不是这意思  谁找我
No, that's -- what is this?
是我办公室打来的
Uh-oh, it is. It's my office.
得接一下
Got to take it.
-喂  -菲尔
- Hello? - Phil?
克莱尔
Claire?
全世界最好的房产中介
World's greatest realtor.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
你头发出汗了
Your hair is sweating.
那是因为看到朋友们我太激动了
That's 'cause I'm excited to see my friends.
快走  小家伙
Let's go, buddy.
你们全是菲尔的客户吗
Are you all clients of Phil's?
显然是的
Apparently.
你们不可能碰到更好的人了
Well, you could not be in better hands.
我在人生最低潮时认识了菲尔
I met Phil when I was at such a rocky place in my life.
早上中午夜晚  他随叫随到
He was available to me morning, noon, and night.
当然他帮我找到了梦想之家
Of course he found me my dream house,
但最棒的还不在这一点
but that wasn't the best part.
菲尔教会我如何再次相信男人
Phil taught me how to trust a man again,
我想他的目的不在卖房子  而是帮人
and I think that was always his plan.
我目的不在卖房子  而是帮人
That was always my plan.
我碰到那样的前夫  让我再次相信男人
And it was not easy for me to trust a man
还真是不太容易
after the husband that I'd had.
那家伙把工具随便扔在院子里
This guys left tools in the yard,
让孩子们乱来
let the kids run wild.
很高兴见到你  克莱尔
Well, great to see you, Claire.
他总是打断我说话
He was always interrupting me.
他戴的睡眠眼罩真是笑死人了
And he wore the most ridiculous sleep-mask thing.
我的天  听起来好娘啊
Oh, god, sounds like such a diva.
也许他是对光很敏感
Or he's photosensitive,
这毛病很严重的
which is a real condition.
他从来不听我的意见
Never took my advice.
这是最糟糕的
You know, that's the worst part.
他从来没说过抱歉  一次也没有
He never -- he never said he was sorry just one time.
我只想听他说一句
I would kill to have heard,
"克莱尔  你是对的"
"Claire, you were right."
她是对的
She was right.
大声点
Louder.
我不喜欢你的这一面
I do not love this side of you.
多谢你帮我赢回了电脑
Thanks for winning my computer back.
还有我的钱  真是太厉害了
And getting me all my money. That was awesome.
如果我那时收手就好了
Yeah, if only I had stopped there,
但我就是不懂见好就收
but I had to go back down.
我太贪心了  又粗心大意
I got greedy, and I was careless.
我记得在学校学过一个寓言
There's a story about that I remember from school.
伊卡洛斯飞得离儿子太近
Icarus flew too close to his son.
[希腊神话  飞得离太阳太近  翅膀上的蜡熔掉了]
我想他们的翅膀撞上了
I think their wings bumped.
其中有一个掉了下去  他们可能是鸭子
One of them fell. They might have been ducks.
总之  教训就是  你得注意点儿
Anyway, the lesson is, is that you have to pay attention.
否则要付出终极代价
Or pay the ultimate price.
可以走了吗  亲爱的
Shall we, my dear?
不用等门
Don't wait up.
要等
Wait up.